viralheat.com 2015-03-21

# Privacy Policy | Viralheat

Last updated: June 29, 2009

**Viralheat, Inc. (Viralheat, “we”, or “us”) respects the privacy of its users. This privacy policy (this “Policy”) describes Viralheat’s collection, use, and disclosure of personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) through its services (“Services”) offered through www.Viralheat.com (the “Site”).**

**Consent.**

BY USING OUR SITE OR OUR SERVICES, OR OTHERWISE SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW. If you do not agree with these terms, do not provide any Personal Information to us and do not use our Services. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, or if you choose not to provide us with any required Personal Information, we may not be able to provide you with certain of our Services that can be offered only if we have access to certain Personal Information.

**Aggregated and other non-personally identifiable information.**

“Personal Information,” as used in this Policy, is information that specifically identifies an individual, such as an individual’s name, address, telephone number, or e-mail address. Personal Information also includes information about an individual’s activities, such as information about his or her activity on the Site and the Services, and demographic information, such as date of birth, gender, geographic area, and preferences, when any of this information is linked to Personal Information that identifies that individual.

Personal Information does not include “aggregate” or other non-personally identifiable information. Aggregate information is information that we collect about a group or category of products, services, or users that is not personally identifiable or from which individual identities are removed. We may use and disclose aggregate information, and other non-personally identifiable information, for various purposes in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

**Collection of Personal Information.**

If you register with us as a subscriber to our Services, we collect Personal Information in order to provide the Services to you. We require that you provide your name, postal address, and e-mail address. You also need to choose a password, which will be required to gain access to portions of our Site or our Services that are reserved for subscribers. To receive Viralheat Alert Services, you may have to provide payment or other necessary information. This includes, for example, billing information, and the name of your employer, if applicable. We may also collect other personal information, such as demographic information, and information about your interests and preferences, in connection with your use of the Site and our Services.

**Passive information collection.**

When you visit the Site and use our Services, some information is automatically collected, such as your IP address, browser type, system type, the content and pages that you access on the Site or our Services, “referring URL” (i.e., the page from which you navigated to the Site), the pages you navigate to on the Site, and from which you leave the Site, as well as the time you spend on the Site or otherwise using our Services.

We collect this information passively using technologies such as standard server logs, cookies, and clear GIFs (also known as “Web beacons”). We use passively-collected information to administer, operate, and improve the Site, our Services, and our other services and systems, and to provide services and content that are tailored to you. If we link or associate any information gathered through passive means with Personal Information, we treat the combined information as Personal Information under this policy. Otherwise, we use information collected by passive means in non-personally identifiable form only.

Also, please be aware that third parties may set cookies on your hard drive or use other means of passively collecting information about your use of their services or content. We do not have access to, or control over, these third-party means of passive data collection.

**How we use the information we collect.**

We use Personal Information in order to provide and enhance the Services offered on our Site:

  1. To issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments;
  2. To provide tips or guidance on how to use our Site and our Services, inform you of new features on our Site and our Services, or provide other information that may be of interest to users;
  3. To personalize the Services we provide to you and tailor your experience at our Site to your interests;
  4. To send you e-mails, e-newsletters, personalized offers via direct messaging or other communications about our services, if you have subscribed to receive this information or you have not advised us that you do not wish to receive such communications;
  5. To manage our Site and our Services, diagnose technical problems, improve content, and allocate the resources of our systems;
  6. To investigate, detect, and protect Viralheat and third parties against, error, negligence, breach of contract, fraud, theft and other unlawful activities;
  7. In connection with the sale, merger, spin-off, or other corporate reorganization, or in the event of our bankruptcy or insolvency, in which case the information is transferred or assigned to a third party as one of our business assets;
  8. To audit compliance with our policies and contractual obligations;
  9. As permitted by, and to comply with, any legal or regulatory requirements or provisions; or
  10. For any other purpose to which you consent.

**Disclosure of Personal Information.**

From time to time, we may disclose your Personal Information as follows:

  1. To third party service providers so that they may provide services, such as payment processing services or website maintenance and security services, to us;
  2. to third-party services as incident to the rendition of some features of the Site and our Services;
  3. To protect our Site and our Services, and our rights under our Terms of Service; to protect ourselves against liability or prevent fraudulent activity; or where we believe it is necessary to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain;
  4. In connection with the sale, merger, spin-off, or other corporate reorganization, or in the event of our bankruptcy or insolvency, in which case the information is transferred or assigned to a third party as one of our business assets;
  5. Where the information is public;
  6. To our insurers and to regulatory agencies and government enforcement agencies;
  7. To comply with a subpoena or warrant issued by, or an order made by, a court, person, or body that we believe in good faith to have authority to compel the production of information, or to comply with the rules of any such court, person, or body relating to the production of records;
  8. If we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule, or guideline requires the disclosure of Personal Information to third parties;
  9. To one or more persons who needs the information because of an emergency that threatens the life, health, or security of an identifiable person or group; and
  10. Where we deem that disclosure of Personal Information is necessary to collect monies owing to us.

**Choice.**

You may opt out of receiving commercial communications from us at any time by following the instructions given in the communication or by emailing us at privacy@Viralheat.com with your request.

**Your access to and control over Personal Information.**

You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address given on our website:

  1. See what Personal Information we have about you, if any.
  2. Change/correct any Personal Information we have about you.
  3. Have us delete any Personal Information we have about you (we may, however, be unable to provide certain of our Services without such Personal Information).
  4. Express any concern you have about our use of your Personal Information.

You may also be provided the ability to review and update certain Personal Information (e.g., billing or account information) in our Services.

**Security.**

We use commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of Personal Information. We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission of information, we make commercially reasonable efforts to ensure the security of our systems. Please note, however, that this is not a guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

**Links.**

The Site contains links to third-party sites and services. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites and services. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of any other site or service that collects personally identifiable information.

**Remarketing Pixel.**

AdWords Remarketing is a Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting service provided by Google. It connects the activity of www.viralheat.com with the Adwords advertising network and the Doubleclick Cookie. You can opt out of the cookie tracking here: http://google.com/settings/ads/onweb/optout?hl=en

Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data. Place of processing: USA. – Find the [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

**Changes to the Privacy Policy.**

This Policy may be revised periodically without further notice to you and this will be reflected by a “last updated” date above. Please revisit this page to stay aware of any changes. In general, we only use your Personal Information in the manner described in the Policy in effect when we received that Personal Information. Your continued use of the Site constitutes your agreement to this Policy and any future revisions.

For revisions to this Policy that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of Personal Information you have provided to us, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you and obtain your consent before implementing such revisions with respect to such information.

**Contacting Us.**

If you have questions regarding this Policy, its implementation, failure to adhere to this Policy, and/or our general practices, please contact us.
